<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/paul/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paul on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:08:46 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/paul/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paul teaches same gospel as the Jerusalem church?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-same-gospel-is-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 15:08:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-same-gospel-is-myth/</guid>
      <description>Paul made a trip back to Jerusalem in approximately 55 AD. By this time, the Jerusalem church has been thriving for over 20 years. Paul has been teaching what he calls &amp;ldquo;my gospel&amp;rdquo; for approximately 15 years.
It&amp;rsquo;s rather remarkable, but the Jerusalem church now has thousands of followers, and they don&amp;rsquo;t even KNOW what Paul has been teaching, except for some rumors.
Paul presents himself before some very concerned elders of the Jerusaelem church as described in Acts 21:18-22.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 09 28 the Greatest Gift</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-28-the-greatest-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 11:02:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-28-the-greatest-gift/</guid>
      <description>Theme and targeted passages We can receive no greater gift than a relationship with God.
Targeted passages: Romans 5:6-11,18-21
I agree with the opening thesis above. I strongly question whether the targeted passages give us the means to achieve that.
I might have started with something like Isaiah 56.
Keeping the law is impossible - Romans 5:6-8 The quarterly does a wonderful job making something perfectly clear about Romans 5:6-8. On page 46, we find the following commentary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The law is for those that despise it?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/law-for-those-that-reject-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/law-for-those-that-reject-it/</guid>
      <description>In 1 Timothy 1:5-10, Paul speaks of a few doctrines he embraces, then switches to condemnation of his ideological enemies:
Certain persons, by swerving from these [doctrines], have wandered away into vain discussion, desiring to be teachers of the law, without understanding either what they are saying or the things about which they make confident assertions. Now we know that the law is good, if one uses it lawfully, understanding this, that the law is not laid down for the just but for the lawless and disobedient, for the ungodly and sinners, for the unholy and profane, for those who strike their fathers and mothers, for murderers, the sexually immoral, men who practice homosexuality, enslavers, liars, perjurers, and whatever else is contrary to sound doctrine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul was subservient to Gamaliel?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-and-gamaliel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 09:53:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-and-gamaliel/</guid>
      <description>During his trial in Jerusalem in Acts 22, Paul of Tarsus makes an interesting claim.
“I am a Jew, born in Tarsus in Cilicia, but brought up in this city, educated at the feet of Gamaliel according to the strict manner of the law of our fathers, being zealous for God as all of you are this day. I persecuted this Way to the death, binding and delivering to prison both men and women, as the high priest and the whole council of elders can bear me witness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Did Not Learn From Apostles</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-did-not-learn-from-apostles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 22:15:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-did-not-learn-from-apostles/</guid>
      <description>In John 17, a prayer is recorded in which Jesus seems to pray a priestly style blessing upon his twelve apostles. This is the last act of Jesus prior to his arrest according to this gospel account. It seems as if Jesus is praying a special anointing upon them.
The prayer includes several interesting things:
John 17:6-10 They were given to him by God, apparently meaning God selected them. Jesus manifested the name of God (Yehovah) to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>According to WHAT scriptures Paul??</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-unknown-prophecy-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 20:28:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-unknown-prophecy-reference/</guid>
      <description>Paul in 1 Corinthians 15:1-11 delivers a startling revelation:
For I delivered to you as of first importance what I also received: that Christ died for our sins in accordance with the Scriptures, that he was buried, that he was raised on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures
Naturally, there were no New Testaments floating around in those days since Paul&amp;rsquo;s epistles were first fragments to emerge. This would have to be one of those prophecies the Jews were so stupid for not reading, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which side of the faith-works dispute is inspired?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/faith-works-dispute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:45:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/faith-works-dispute/</guid>
      <description>Justification. Paul says works have nothing to do with it. Galatians 2:17:
Knowing that a man is not justified by the works of the law, but by the faith of Jesus Christ, even we have believed in Jesus Christ, that we might be justified by the faith of Christ, and not by the works of the law: for by the works of the law shall no flesh be justified.
James on the other hand disputes this in James 2:14-26:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Jesus dispute Paul&#39;s &#39;Roman Road&#39; method of salvation?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/jesus-disputes-confess-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:15:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/jesus-disputes-confess-mouth/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard an &amp;ldquo;altar call&amp;rdquo; in a Baptist church, it almost always concludes with Romans 10:9:
That if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe* in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved.
The statement is absolute. There&amp;rsquo;s no maybe in the context.
So what&amp;rsquo;s the problem?
Well, the problem is that Jesus disputes it in Matthew 7:21-23.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sinai - out of bondage, or in?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/out-of-bondage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 16:20:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/out-of-bondage/</guid>
      <description>Bondage. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine a situation in which that word would be anything but dreaded, right? The word itself invokes in us a visceral response similar to words like hunger or loneliness or helplessness. It&amp;rsquo;s not something desirable. It&amp;rsquo;s something to be avoided.
In Exodus 20:2, we find that very word in the first of the &amp;ldquo;Ten Commandments&amp;rdquo;:
I am the LORD thy God, which have brought thee out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of bondage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Apostles?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/how-many-apostles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 23:02:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/how-many-apostles/</guid>
      <description>Crisis. Acts 1. Jesus has just departed into the clouds. Former “Apostle” Judas was gone. He had to be replaced. He was required to “have been with us the whole time Jesus was living among us.” (Acts 1:21) Two men were found equally worthy. (Acts 1:23) Could they have both? Nope. The number was restored to exactly twelve (Acts 1:26). Eleven was not okay. Thirteen was not okay. Twelve. Exactly twelve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Paul practice fund-raising?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/why-is-fundraising-okay-for-paul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 19:17:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/why-is-fundraising-okay-for-paul/</guid>
      <description>Jesus first sent his twelve Apostles on The Great Commission, this time to Jews only, in Matthew 10:5-10. He prescribed a certain behavior for them to follow. This included a prohibition on fundraising:
You received without paying, give without paying. Acquire no gold or silver or copper for your belts. While Paul was self-declared as an Apostle likewise, he had different behavior.
He dedicated an entire chapter, Phillippians 4 to the subject of fund raising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Paul a Fundraiser?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/is-paul-a-fundraiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 14:36:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/is-paul-a-fundraiser/</guid>
      <description>When it is pointed out that Paul engaged in fundraising activities in Phillippians 4, some respond by saying something like this:
&amp;ldquo;Paul was not accepting a &amp;ldquo;seed money&amp;rdquo; for blessing like the TV preachers. He was just accepting small gifts for his own personal needs. It was not something that could be called &amp;lsquo;fund raising&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;
Paul seemed to be taking up a collection for &amp;ldquo;the poor&amp;rdquo; in Jerusalem as we see in Romans 15:25-26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writings of Paul originally rejected by Jerusalem leadership</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 19:17:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</guid>
      <description>Did the original church have official endorsed writings?
Sadly, the answer by most preachers is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;. They will recount that &amp;ldquo;canon of scripture&amp;rdquo; was established much later. However, there was an early document that received endorsement, but often does not get the recognition it deserves. The history of this document exists today in your own bible for anyone who cares to look.
The Council at Jerusalem A meeting took place between Paul and the Jerusalem church in approximately 50 A.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
