<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Salvation on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/salvation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Salvation on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:42:17 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/salvation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Saves</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2026-01-11-jesus-saves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:42:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2026-01-11-jesus-saves/</guid>
      <description>Handout from Greg I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with the handout Greg sent by email which will be the focus of the lesson. My reactions are indented along the way.
Life Connection In a world where various religious groups seek their own interpretations of salvation, and many individuals question its necessity, even the most self-absorbed among us occasionally sense an emptiness, a yearning for something deeper.
Most would be relieved to have just one solid answer defining exactly what salvation is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul misrepresents Psalm 14</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-misquotes-psalm-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:07:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-misquotes-psalm-14/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard the &amp;ldquo;Roman Road&amp;rdquo; to salvation as presented by Baptists, Pentecostals and many others, it includes the following as it&amp;rsquo;s first point taken from Romans 3:10.
&amp;hellip; as it is written: “None is righteous, no, not one&amp;quot;;
Now wait, Paul is suggesting he didn&amp;rsquo;t even author this concept. He&amp;rsquo;s describing that it&amp;rsquo;s written, and it&amp;rsquo;s therefore authoritative. So, &amp;ldquo;as it is written&amp;rdquo;, written where? Paul is apparently loosely quoting this from Psalm 14:1-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which side of the faith-works dispute is inspired?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/faith-works-dispute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:45:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/faith-works-dispute/</guid>
      <description>Justification. Paul says works have nothing to do with it. Galatians 2:17:
Knowing that a man is not justified by the works of the law, but by the faith of Jesus Christ, even we have believed in Jesus Christ, that we might be justified by the faith of Christ, and not by the works of the law: for by the works of the law shall no flesh be justified.
James on the other hand disputes this in James 2:14-26:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Jesus dispute Paul&#39;s &#39;Roman Road&#39; method of salvation?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/jesus-disputes-confess-mouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 19:15:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/jesus-disputes-confess-mouth/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard an &amp;ldquo;altar call&amp;rdquo; in a Baptist church, it almost always concludes with Romans 10:9:
That if thou shalt confess with thy mouth the Lord Jesus, and shalt believe* in thine heart that God hath raised him from the dead, thou shalt be saved.
The statement is absolute. There&amp;rsquo;s no maybe in the context.
So what&amp;rsquo;s the problem?
Well, the problem is that Jesus disputes it in Matthew 7:21-23.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
