<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants and Raves on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants and Raves on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 18:33:30 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why does Hebrews pretend to quote Jeremiah, then misrepresent it?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/hebrews-misquotes-jer-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 18:33:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/hebrews-misquotes-jer-31/</guid>
      <description>The definition of the promise commonly called the &amp;ldquo;New Covenant&amp;rdquo; is found in Jeremiah 31:31-34.
For some reason, the writer of Hebrews misquotes Jeremiah 31:32.
not like the covenant that I made with their fathers on the day when I took them by the hand to bring them out of the land of Egypt, my covenant that they broke, though I was their husband, declares the LORD.
Instead, the unknown writer of Hebrews says this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sinai - out of bondage, or in?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/out-of-bondage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 16:20:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/out-of-bondage/</guid>
      <description>Bondage. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine a situation in which that word would be anything but dreaded, right? The word itself invokes in us a visceral response similar to words like hunger or loneliness or helplessness. It&amp;rsquo;s not something desirable. It&amp;rsquo;s something to be avoided.
In Exodus 20:2, we find that very word in the first of the &amp;ldquo;Ten Commandments&amp;rdquo;:
I am the LORD thy God, which have brought thee out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of bondage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Christianity really believe in the &#39;Ten Commandments&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/fourth-commandment-rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 07:35:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/fourth-commandment-rejected/</guid>
      <description>In Exodus 31:13, Yehovah declares the following:
Speak thou also unto the children of Israel, saying, Verily my sabbaths ye shall keep: for it is a sign between me and you throughout your generations; that ye may know that I am the LORD that doth sanctify you.
It is further emphasized in Ezekiel 20:12-20.
Christians have fought valiantly to preserve The Ten Commmandments on plaques on courthouses all over the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Christianity have an inexplicable compulsion to ignore the Sabbaths?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/sabbath-sign-rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 07:12:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/sabbath-sign-rejected/</guid>
      <description>In Exodus 31:13, Yehovah declares the following:
Speak thou also unto the children of Israel, saying, Verily my sabbaths ye shall keep: for it is a sign between me and you throughout your generations; that ye may know that I am the LORD that doth sanctify you.
It is further emphasized in Ezekiel 20:12-20.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to demonstrate both Jesus and the early church observed Sabbaths both before and after his ascension:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is atonement by righteousness and charity ignored?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/charity-atones-for-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:34:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/charity-atones-for-sin/</guid>
      <description>There is a foundational Christian doctrine that is often stated:
Without the shedding of blood, there is no forgiveness of sins.
The primary source for the doctrine is Hebrews 9:22.
According to Yehovah, charity and righteousness atone for sin.
Proverbs 10:2 - righteousness delivers from death Proverbs 11:4 - delivers from death Proverbs 16:6 - steadfast love atones for iniquity Proverbs 21:3 - superior to blood sacrifice in His eyes Hosea 6:6 - what he really desires Daniel 4:27 - Lengthens prosperity </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paralytic story - Where Is Shed Blood?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paralytic-where-is-shed-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 15:59:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paralytic-where-is-shed-blood/</guid>
      <description>There is a doctrine that is often stated:
Without the shedding of blood, there is no forgiveness of sins.
Though the primary source is Hebrews 9:22, secondary sources for the doctrine would be Ephesians 1:7 and Matthew 26:28.
The problem arises when a story emerges in which God Incarnate himself breaks this rule. In the story of the paralytic, there is no shedding of blood an any of the accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 09 21 the Greatest Sin</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-21-the-greatest-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:34:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-21-the-greatest-sin/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the &amp;ldquo;Point&amp;rdquo; of this lesson The point of the lesson is thus described:
The greatest sin is never trusting Jesus.
I do walk to this discussion with loyalties. My God is Yehovah, the God of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob. The entirety of my trust is upon him. To the extent to which Jesus speaks for Yehovah in the role of a prophet, I likewise trust Jesus like I would Ezekiel or Jeremiah or Hosea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did Jesus say obey what&#39;s read from Moses&#39; seat?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/obey-readings-from-moses-seat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 18:20:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/obey-readings-from-moses-seat/</guid>
      <description>In Matthew 23:1-3, Jesus is quoted saying:
Then Jesus said to the crowds and to his disciples, “The scribes and the Pharisees sit on Moses’ seat, so do and observe whatever they tell you, but not the works they do&amp;hellip;.
What specifically is read from Moses&amp;rsquo; seat? (hint, think who&amp;rsquo;s buried in Grant&amp;rsquo;s tomb). The law of God as delivered to Moses of course!
Is it possible that Christians think God&amp;rsquo;s law is a burden, and schoolmaster and against us because of something Paul says?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 09 14 the Greatest Need</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-14-the-greatest-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:58:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-14-the-greatest-need/</guid>
      <description>The first section emphasizes obtaining help often &amp;ldquo;requires a certain professional&amp;rdquo;.
This story is one of the few that can be found in all four gospel accounts.
Matthew 9:1-8 Mark 2:1-12 Luke 5:17-26 John 5:5-17 An interesting statement is found in Luke 5:17. It states that &amp;ldquo;the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power&amp;rdquo; was &amp;ldquo;in Jesus&amp;rdquo;. That would be quite different than the power originating in Jesus. It implies an anointing similar to Elijah or Moses or the prophets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paralytic sins forgiven with no repentance?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paralytic-repentence-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:22:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paralytic-repentence-missing/</guid>
      <description>The story of the &amp;ldquo;Healing of the paralytic&amp;rdquo; is found in four places:
Matthew 9:1-8 Mark 2:1-12 Luke 5:17-26 John 5:8-9 Where&amp;rsquo;s repentance?? Nowhere in any of the accounts does the paralyzed man repent of anything. Is repentance optional? Certainly seems important elsewhere:
Matthew 3:2 Matthew 4:17 Mark 1:15 Mark 6:12 Luke 13:3-5 Acts 2:38 In Luke 17:3-4, people are not required to forgive except there&amp;rsquo;s repentance.
Why is there no concern about whether this man had repented or not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could Ezekiel Forgive Sin?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/could-ezekiel-forgive-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 13:29:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/could-ezekiel-forgive-sin/</guid>
      <description>Ezekiel addressed as Son of Man 63 times The book of Ezekiel is chunked full of examples in which Yehovah addresses him as Son of Man. One example from Ezekiel 2:6-8
And you, son of man, be not afraid of them, nor be afraid of their words, though briers and thorns are with you and you sit on scorpions.[fn] Be not afraid of their words, nor be dismayed at their looks, for they are a rebellious house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who decides expiration dates on New Testament promises?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/who-picks-expiration-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 12:46:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/who-picks-expiration-dates/</guid>
      <description>There is a pretty amazing promise made in Mark 16:17-20:
And these signs will accompany those who believe: in my name they will cast out demons; they will speak in new tongues; they will pick up serpents with their hands; and if they drink any deadly poison, it will not hurt them; they will lay their hands on the sick, and they will recover. So then the Lord Jesus, after he had spoken to them, was taken up into heaven and sat down at the right hand of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affliction Removed by Forgiveness</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/affliction-removed-by-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 12:24:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/affliction-removed-by-forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>The story of the &amp;ldquo;Healing of the paralytic&amp;rdquo; is found in four places:
Matthew 9:1-8 Mark 2:1-12 Luke 5:17-26 John 5:8-9 Modern application A veteran rolls his wheelchair down the aisle, a small quilt covering the stumps he has remaining for legs. He is led through the plan of salvation.
&amp;ldquo;Are my sins forgiven?&amp;rdquo;, he asks.
&amp;ldquo;Yes, your sins are forgiven.&amp;rdquo;
He looks searchingly. &amp;ldquo;When do you get to the part about taking up my chair and walking?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did Jesus affirm someone afflicted has sin that caused it?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/presumption-sin-causes-affliction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 11:24:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/presumption-sin-causes-affliction/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re afflicted because you sinned! The entire book of Job is on a certain theme. Starting with Job 2:11, Job&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; come to &amp;ldquo;comfort&amp;rdquo; him. They observe the horror of his afflictions. They all determine in unison that his condition was related to his sin. For forty painful chapters, multiple friends of Job join in, each affirming his affliction was because of some sin they could not identify.
Finally, in Job 42:7-42:9, Yehovah rebukes the friends for this false presumption, and in Job 42:10-17 restores the blessings to Job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 08 24 Generosity</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-08-24-generosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 11:23:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-08-24-generosity/</guid>
      <description>The opening section does a good job introducing generosity using the example of Warren Buffet, who is said to give 99% of his income away. However, it&amp;rsquo;s pointed out he is an agnostic and generosity is a &amp;ldquo;heart issue&amp;rdquo;, I suppose implying he is lacking the right heart. It concludes by identifying the target.
In our study, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how God&amp;rsquo;s abundant grace moves us toward a generous lifestyle.
Well, that sounds good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Apostles?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/how-many-apostles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 23:02:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/how-many-apostles/</guid>
      <description>Crisis. Acts 1. Jesus has just departed into the clouds. Former “Apostle” Judas was gone. He had to be replaced. He was required to “have been with us the whole time Jesus was living among us.” (Acts 1:21) Two men were found equally worthy. (Acts 1:23) Could they have both? Nope. The number was restored to exactly twelve (Acts 1:26). Eleven was not okay. Thirteen was not okay. Twelve. Exactly twelve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did False Witnesses Against Stephen Lie?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/did-false-witnesses-against-stephen-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:41:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/did-false-witnesses-against-stephen-lie/</guid>
      <description>In the early days of the Jerusalem church, the Pharisees cornered a follower of Jesus named Stephen. The entirety of the story is found in Acts 6. The religious leaders &amp;ldquo;could not withstand the wisdom and the Spirit with which he was speaking&amp;rdquo;. They sought to trap him another way:
And they stirred up the people, and the elders, and the scribes, and came upon him, and caught him, and brought him to the council, And set up false witnesses, which said, This man ceaseth not to speak blasphemous words against this holy place, and the law: For we have heard him say, that this Jesus of Nazareth shall destroy this place, and shall change the customs which Moses delivered us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:05:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/recommendations/</guid>
      <description>These are somewhat random articles I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;put to paper&amp;rdquo; as I think of them. I&amp;rsquo;m human, I don&amp;rsquo;t profess any divine empowerment. These questions are constructed from my own study with a hope of enlightenment my own prayer. I recommend you question everything, and that includes me. (yeah, I know, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the contact page working yet&amp;hellip;sorry).
I&amp;rsquo;m creating these articles as &amp;ldquo;single conversation sized&amp;rdquo; bites. I anticipate this being a collection that grows over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does Paul practice fund-raising?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/why-is-fundraising-okay-for-paul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 19:17:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/why-is-fundraising-okay-for-paul/</guid>
      <description>Jesus first sent his twelve Apostles on The Great Commission, this time to Jews only, in Matthew 10:5-10. He prescribed a certain behavior for them to follow. This included a prohibition on fundraising:
You received without paying, give without paying. Acquire no gold or silver or copper for your belts. While Paul was self-declared as an Apostle likewise, he had different behavior.
He dedicated an entire chapter, Phillippians 4 to the subject of fund raising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Paul a Fundraiser?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/is-paul-a-fundraiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 14:36:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/is-paul-a-fundraiser/</guid>
      <description>When it is pointed out that Paul engaged in fundraising activities in Phillippians 4, some respond by saying something like this:
&amp;ldquo;Paul was not accepting a &amp;ldquo;seed money&amp;rdquo; for blessing like the TV preachers. He was just accepting small gifts for his own personal needs. It was not something that could be called &amp;lsquo;fund raising&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;
Paul seemed to be taking up a collection for &amp;ldquo;the poor&amp;rdquo; in Jerusalem as we see in Romans 15:25-26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanity Declaration - please join me</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/sanity-declaration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 12:08:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/sanity-declaration/</guid>
      <description>I hold it to be self-evident that nobody can do their job as senator or congressman when the bills put before them are thousands of pages long. I think you will all agree with me, this is not just sometimes, this is ALWAYS an effort to hide the evil that&amp;rsquo;s within. I took action by creating a document I&amp;rsquo;m calling the Sanity Declaration. I&amp;rsquo;ve already mailed it to several congressmen and senators asking them to sign it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Tennessee is persecuting property owners</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/tn-off-grid-persecution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 12:57:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/tn-off-grid-persecution/</guid>
      <description>This couple, Matt and Cass are simply exercising their God-given rights, but liberals can&amp;rsquo;t stand it when you&amp;rsquo;re independent of their control and truly free.
Tennessee obviously has too much money at it&amp;rsquo;s disposal. It has started the persecution tactics exercised in tyrannical states like New York or Massachusets. We obviously need fewer government employees to harass people like these who only want to be left alone in their little cabin on their own property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitulation Video</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/capitulation-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:11:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/capitulation-video/</guid>
      <description>Is Joe Biden really in charge? Or is something very historic taking place? I personally believe we are currently in a state of military continuity-of-government. I believe we have reason to be very very exicted.This documentary explains how we got there.
There are two ways to watch this video.
With commentary from Phil Godlewsky This version has thought-provoking commentary mixed in as it is reviewed. Phil wastes a lot of time in the intro, so I have the link set to begin at the 18:40 mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing Youtube Artists</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/amazing-youtube-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 08:00:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/amazing-youtube-artists/</guid>
      <description>Great music is not always endorsed by deep pockets. The Youtube platform has allowed some of the best moments in music to be captured and shared. There are several artists that are either earning noteriety or gaining it, not because some hot-shot on Music Row decided it, but because we-the-people loved them. Here are some of my favorites.
Chelsea Constable I&amp;rsquo;m putting Chelsea and Grace at the top of the list because they illustrate what my post is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writings of Paul originally rejected by Jerusalem leadership</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 19:17:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</guid>
      <description>Did the original church have official endorsed writings?
Sadly, the answer by most preachers is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;. They will recount that &amp;ldquo;canon of scripture&amp;rdquo; was established much later. However, there was an early document that received endorsement, but often does not get the recognition it deserves. The history of this document exists today in your own bible for anyone who cares to look.
The Council at Jerusalem A meeting took place between Paul and the Jerusalem church in approximately 50 A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Illustration from Victor Hugo et son temps (1881) This is a blog I have created to throw a few thoughts out there and also to experiment with a few technology tools:
Created with Hugo. Saved on Github Publishes changes upon check-in to Github Pages Publish kicked-off at check-in via Github Actions. Uses the Ananke theme. Added custom support for highlighting bible references from Blue Letter Bible. Added ability to render Mermaid Diagrams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/contact/</guid>
      <description>Not currently supported Check out Formspree for a simple, free form service.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
