<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rants and Raves on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rants and Raves on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 12:57:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State of Tennessee is persecuting property owners</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/tn-off-grid-persecution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 12:57:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/tn-off-grid-persecution/</guid>
      <description>This couple, Matt and Cass are simply exercising their God-given rights, but liberals can&amp;rsquo;t stand it when you&amp;rsquo;re independent of their control and truly free.
Tennessee obviously has too much money at it&amp;rsquo;s disposal. It has started the persecution tactics exercised in tyrannical states like New York or Massachusets. We obviously need fewer government employees to harass people like these who only want to be left alone in their little cabin on their own property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitulation Video</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/capitulation-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:11:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/capitulation-video/</guid>
      <description>Is Joe Biden really in charge? Or is something very historic taking place? I personally believe we are currently in a state of military continuity-of-government. I believe we have reason to be very very exicted.This documentary explains how we got there.
There are two ways to watch this video.
With commentary from Phil Godlewsky This version has thought-provoking commentary mixed in as it is reviewed. Phil wastes a lot of time in the intro, so I have the link set to begin at the 18:40 mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing Youtube Artists</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/amazing-youtube-artists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 08:00:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/amazing-youtube-artists/</guid>
      <description>Great music is not always endorsed by deep pockets. The Youtube platform has allowed some of the best moments in music to be captured and shared. There are several artists that are either earning noteriety or gaining it, not because some hot-shot on Music Row decided it, but because we-the-people loved them. Here are some of my favorites.
Chelsea Constable I&amp;rsquo;m putting Chelsea and Grace at the top of the list because they illustrate what my post is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writings of Paul originally rejected by Jerusalem leadership</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 19:17:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</guid>
      <description>Did the original church have official endorsed writings?
Sadly, the answer by most preachers is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;. They will recount that &amp;ldquo;canon of scripture&amp;rdquo; was established much later. However, there was an early document that received endorsement, but often does not get the recognition it deserves. The history of this document exists today in your own bible for anyone who cares to look.
The Council at Jerusalem A meeting took place between Paul and the Jerusalem church in approximately 50 A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Illustration from Victor Hugo et son temps (1881) This is a blog I have created to throw a few thoughts out there and also to experiment with a few technology tools:
Created with Hugo. Saved on Github Publishes changes upon check-in to Github Pages Publish kicked-off at check-in via Github Actions. Uses the Ananke theme. Added custom support for highlighting bible references from Blue Letter Bible. Added ability to render Mermaid Diagrams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/contact/</guid>
      <description>Not currently supported. Check out Formspree for a simple, free form service.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
