<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MAGA on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/maga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MAGA on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 12:57:40 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/maga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State of Tennessee is persecuting property owners</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/tn-off-grid-persecution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 12:57:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/tn-off-grid-persecution/</guid>
      <description>This couple, Matt and Cass are simply exercising their God-given rights, but liberals can&amp;rsquo;t stand it when you&amp;rsquo;re independent of their control and truly free.
Tennessee obviously has too much money at it&amp;rsquo;s disposal. It has started the persecution tactics exercised in tyrannical states like New York or Massachusets. We obviously need fewer government employees to harass people like these who only want to be left alone in their little cabin on their own property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitulation Video</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/capitulation-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:11:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/capitulation-video/</guid>
      <description>Is Joe Biden really in charge? Or is something very historic taking place? I personally believe we are currently in a state of military continuity-of-government. I believe we have reason to be very very exicted.This documentary explains how we got there.
There are two ways to watch this video.
With commentary from Phil Godlewsky This version has thought-provoking commentary mixed in as it is reviewed. Phil wastes a lot of time in the intro, so I have the link set to begin at the 18:40 mark.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
