<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sunday School on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sunday School on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025-12-21 When Understanding Falls Short</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-12-21-when-understanding-falls-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:30:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-12-21-when-understanding-falls-short/</guid>
      <description>God will use anyone who surrenders to Him Page 39 starts with an inspirational story of Oseola McCarty who lived a life in servitude to others, only to leave the entirety of her worldly accumulation to help others. Indeed, her story illustrates the main point of the lesson. Truly inspirational.
Appearance by an angel The Luke 1:26-30 passage on page 40 tells the Luke version of the birth narrative. Unfortunately, the author makes an observation that is not implied in the text:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Circumstances Fall Short</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-12-14-when-circumstances-fall-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:41:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-12-14-when-circumstances-fall-short/</guid>
      <description>Source text: 2 Corinthians 1:8-10; 2 Corinthians 12:6-10
Overall lesson I agree mostly with the lesson the author attempted here. It is summarized by a quote from Psalm 62:1.
I am at rest in God alone; my salvation comes from him.
As in many cases, the author supposes the psalmist speaking of &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rdquo; meant &amp;ldquo;Jesus&amp;rdquo;. So the author hears about someday seeing Jesus, but my only context is someday seeing Yehovah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 09 28 the Greatest Gift</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-28-the-greatest-gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 11:02:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-28-the-greatest-gift/</guid>
      <description>Theme and targeted passages We can receive no greater gift than a relationship with God.
Targeted passages: Romans 5:6-11,18-21
I agree with the opening thesis above. I strongly question whether the targeted passages give us the means to achieve that.
I might have started with something like Isaiah 56.
Keeping the law is impossible - Romans 5:6-8 The quarterly does a wonderful job making something perfectly clear about Romans 5:6-8. On page 46, we find the following commentary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 09 21 the Greatest Sin</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-21-the-greatest-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:34:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-21-the-greatest-sin/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the &amp;ldquo;Point&amp;rdquo; of this lesson The point of the lesson is thus described:
The greatest sin is never trusting Jesus.
I do walk to this discussion with loyalties. My God is Yehovah, the God of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob. The entirety of my trust is upon him. To the extent to which Jesus speaks for Yehovah in the role of a prophet, I likewise trust Jesus like I would Ezekiel or Jeremiah or Hosea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 09 14 the Greatest Need</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-14-the-greatest-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:58:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-09-14-the-greatest-need/</guid>
      <description>The first section emphasizes obtaining help often &amp;ldquo;requires a certain professional&amp;rdquo;.
This story is one of the few that can be found in all four gospel accounts.
Matthew 9:1-8 Mark 2:1-12 Luke 5:17-26 John 5:5-17 An interesting statement is found in Luke 5:17. It states that &amp;ldquo;the Lord&amp;rsquo;s power&amp;rdquo; was &amp;ldquo;in Jesus&amp;rdquo;. That would be quite different than the power originating in Jesus. It implies an anointing similar to Elijah or Moses or the prophets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 08 24 Generosity</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-08-24-generosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 11:23:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-08-24-generosity/</guid>
      <description>The opening section does a good job introducing generosity using the example of Warren Buffet, who is said to give 99% of his income away. However, it&amp;rsquo;s pointed out he is an agnostic and generosity is a &amp;ldquo;heart issue&amp;rdquo;, I suppose implying he is lacking the right heart. It concludes by identifying the target.
In our study, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how God&amp;rsquo;s abundant grace moves us toward a generous lifestyle.
Well, that sounds good.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
