<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prophecy on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/prophecy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prophecy on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:16:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/prophecy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remember the Law of Moses</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/day-of-lord-remember-moses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:16:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/day-of-lord-remember-moses/</guid>
      <description>Last chapter in the Christian Old Testament: Malachi 4 1 For, behold, the day cometh, that shall burn as an oven; and all the proud, yea, and all that do wickedly, shall be stubble: and the day that cometh shall burn them up, saith the LORD of hosts, that it shall leave them neither root nor branch. 2 But unto you that fear my name shall the Sun of righteousness arise with healing in his wings; and ye shall go forth, and grow up as calves of the stall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Exodus Prophecy</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/greater-exodus-prophecy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 20:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/greater-exodus-prophecy/</guid>
      <description>In Jeremiah 16:14-15, there is a very interesting prophecy:
“Therefore, behold, the days are coming, declares the LORD, when it shall no longer be said, ‘As the LORD lives who brought up the people of Israel out of the land of Egypt,’but ‘As the LORD lives who brought up the people of Israel out of the north country and out of all the countries where he had driven them.’ For I will bring them back to their own land that I gave to their fathers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>According to WHAT scriptures Paul??</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-unknown-prophecy-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 20:28:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-unknown-prophecy-reference/</guid>
      <description>Paul in 1 Corinthians 15:1-11 delivers a startling revelation:
For I delivered to you as of first importance what I also received: that Christ died for our sins in accordance with the Scriptures, that he was buried, that he was raised on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures
Naturally, there were no New Testaments floating around in those days since Paul&amp;rsquo;s epistles were first fragments to emerge. This would have to be one of those prophecies the Jews were so stupid for not reading, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
