<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prophecy on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/prophecy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prophecy on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:30:06 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/prophecy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025-12-21 When Understanding Falls Short</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-12-21-when-understanding-falls-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:30:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/bsfl/2025-12-21-when-understanding-falls-short/</guid>
      <description>God will use anyone who surrenders to Him Page 39 starts with an inspirational story of Oseola McCarty who lived a life in servitude to others, only to leave the entirety of her worldly accumulation to help others. Indeed, her story illustrates the main point of the lesson. Truly inspirational.
Appearance by an angel The Luke 1:26-30 passage on page 40 tells the Luke version of the birth narrative. Unfortunately, the author makes an observation that is not implied in the text:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we discuss the EARLIEST disclosure of new covenant?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/new-covenant-originates-deu-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 11:32:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/new-covenant-originates-deu-30/</guid>
      <description>Christianity is eager to tie their claim to the &amp;ldquo;New Covenant&amp;rdquo; back to Jeremiah 31:31 in spite of some problems. However, the unmistakable link between Jeremiah 31:33 and Deuteronomy 30:6, both referring to the deployment of the law being written on their hearts&amp;hellip;.well, that is something they don&amp;rsquo;t really want to talk about.
Why?
Well, I can think of a reason or two&amp;hellip;
The Deuteronomy text depicts the original Torah returning to the hearts and minds of people in Deu 30:1, and Christianity is deeply invested in a divestment in the &amp;ldquo;old law&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember the Law of Moses</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/day-of-lord-remember-moses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 13:16:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/day-of-lord-remember-moses/</guid>
      <description>Last chapter in the Christian Old Testament: Malachi 4 1 For, behold, the day cometh, that shall burn as an oven; and all the proud, yea, and all that do wickedly, shall be stubble: and the day that cometh shall burn them up, saith the LORD of hosts, that it shall leave them neither root nor branch. 2 But unto you that fear my name shall the Sun of righteousness arise with healing in his wings; and ye shall go forth, and grow up as calves of the stall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater Exodus Prophecy</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/greater-exodus-prophecy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 20:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/greater-exodus-prophecy/</guid>
      <description>In Jeremiah 16:14-15, there is a very interesting prophecy:
“Therefore, behold, the days are coming, declares the LORD, when it shall no longer be said, ‘As the LORD lives who brought up the people of Israel out of the land of Egypt,’but ‘As the LORD lives who brought up the people of Israel out of the north country and out of all the countries where he had driven them.’ For I will bring them back to their own land that I gave to their fathers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>According to WHAT scriptures Paul??</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-unknown-prophecy-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 20:28:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/paul-unknown-prophecy-reference/</guid>
      <description>Paul in 1 Corinthians 15:1-11 delivers a startling revelation:
For I delivered to you as of first importance what I also received: that Christ died for our sins in accordance with the Scriptures, that he was buried, that he was raised on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures
Naturally, there were no New Testaments floating around in those days since Paul&amp;rsquo;s epistles were first fragments to emerge. This would have to be one of those prophecies the Jews were so stupid for not reading, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
