<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canon on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</title>
    <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/canon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canon on Jeff Ward Rants and Raves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:41:35 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/tags/canon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Did False Witnesses Against Stephen Lie?</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/did-false-witnesses-against-stephen-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 17:41:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/questions/did-false-witnesses-against-stephen-lie/</guid>
      <description>In the early days of the Jerusalem church, the Pharisees cornered a follower of Jesus named Stephen. The entirety of the story is found in Acts 6. The religious leaders &amp;ldquo;could not withstand the wisdom and the Spirit with which he was speaking&amp;rdquo;. They sought to trap him another way:
And they stirred up the people, and the elders, and the scribes, and came upon him, and caught him, and brought him to the council, And set up false witnesses, which said, This man ceaseth not to speak blasphemous words against this holy place, and the law: For we have heard him say, that this Jesus of Nazareth shall destroy this place, and shall change the customs which Moses delivered us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writings of Paul originally rejected by Jerusalem leadership</title>
      <link>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 19:17:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefforyamos.github.io/blog/post/writings_of_paul_were_rejected/</guid>
      <description>Did the original church have official endorsed writings?
Sadly, the answer by most preachers is &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo;. They will recount that &amp;ldquo;canon of scripture&amp;rdquo; was established much later. However, there was an early document that received endorsement, but often does not get the recognition it deserves. The history of this document exists today in your own bible for anyone who cares to look.
The Council at Jerusalem A meeting took place between Paul and the Jerusalem church in approximately 50 A.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
